Hi, and welcome to the short video
where we will look at functional
testing and non-functional testing.
So in this session, we've already looked
at different types of testing and when
that testing is carried out, whether it
be as part of the software development
life cycle, or whether it be carried out
black box testing or white box testing.
But, so what is functional testing and
non-functional testing in relation to that?
So what's the difference between.
So the types of functional testing we have, unit
testing, integration testing, system testing,
interface testing, smoke testing, sanity testing,
regression testing, and acceptance testing.
There are other elements, there may be other
different types of tests that were carried
out, but these are the most common that
you will find of functional testing types.
So this is basically designed to test
the requirements or specifications,
so all the technical details, the data
manipulation processing, and the various
functionalities that you will have within
an application or a piece of software.
But you've also got other testing,
which is non-functional testing.
So what do we mean when we talk
about non-functional testing?
So the non-functional testing element of any
testing process relates to the software testing,
where it's looking at non-functional aspects,
performance, usability, reliability, so stress
what happens to the system when it's under load.
So the different types of testing that you
have are documentation testing, which is
an important element within the software
development, life cycle, performance testing,
so how does the actual application perform?
Does it perform as expected?
Usability, does it meet the usability
standards for the application?
What is expected, security testing,
which is a very important element
within any software application.
Load testing, so what happens when the application
is put under load, which we've already talked
about on a previous page, and volume testing.
So what's the difference between the two?
So if we have a look at this table, you
can think about it in relation to the
parameter, so what is the objective?
What is the objective of functional testing
as opposed to non-functional testing?
So when you look at the objective of functional
testing, it's mainly carried out to verify
and validate that the software, such as login
functions, work as expected, whereas the
non-functional testing helps in verify and
validate the performance of the software.
So if you're doing a
functional test, does it work?
When somebody inputs an expected piece
of information, does the software respond
appropriately, and then you've also got
the key focus area, so functional testing
concentrates on the user requirements.
So what, what the system should do under
any given situation and the processes that
will take place, whereas the non-functional
testing concentrates on the user expectations.
So how, like how is the system built?
How does it interact with the user
and so on, and then ease of use easy
to execute black box test cases.
So, you know, functional testing is easy to
execute and it's quite straightforward you
don't need to know anything under the underlying
code or anything like that, and it's all
about the um, does it perform as expected?
Non-functional testing is easy to execute white
box test cases, and again, this is looking at the
internal structure and implementation process, and
so you can see what's happening inside the box.
Functionality um, so the functional
testing helps describe what the system
should do, whereas the non-functional,
it describes how the system should work.
So the first one is what it should do.
How does it work.
So the functional testing provides the answers
to, to what the functions in the system are
doing, whereas non-functional answers to how
the questions in the system and execution.
So functional testing is executed
before the non-functional testing.
So it always takes place before the non-functional
testing, because this defines the the, the
testing and the processes that are going to be
executed first, where the non-functional only
takes place after the execution has happened.
So as you can see, that's just a
brief overview of the differences.
So in your assessment you'll be asked
to look at what's the difference
between functional and non-functional.
So it may be useful to identify the
different testing methods and use those
as examples to illustrate your answer.
So, unit testing, what kind of
testing is that and why is that done?
What's the difference between that and
a, an element of nonfunctional testing?